领 衔 主 演
艾 尔 · 帕 西 诺          罗 伯 特 · 德 尼 罗
片 名: 盗 火 线
又 译: 烈 火 悍 将
编剧 及 导演
迈 克 尔 · 曼
你现在可以把她留在走廊里
Yeah, you can leave her in the hallway for now.
- 稳住这儿  - 便携X光机在哪儿
- Stabilizing here. - Where's the portable x-ray?
支票  信用卡  还是现金
Check, charge or cash?
现金
Cash. And, uh...
发票写土珊市积氏拆卸公司
...make it out to Jack's Demolition, Tucson.
总数是七百八十八点三元
Seven eighty-eight thirty.
好了
Okay.
嘿
Hey.
和我吃早餐吗
Taking me to breakfast?
不行  我得去见博高
I can't, I'm meeting Bosko.
嘿  云信
Hey, Vincent.
- 妈妈  我的发夹呢  - 嘿  宝贝
- Mom, where are my barrettes? - Hi, sweetie.
- 我看见在厨房桌子上  - 不在那儿  我看过了
- I saw them on the kitchen table. - They're not there. I already checked.
- 喝咖啡吗  - 今天不用上学吗
- Want me to make coffee? - No school today?
爸爸带我去新大厦  然后吃午餐
My dad's taking me to the new building and then to lunch.
到沙发垫子下找
Try under the cushions on the sofa.
他迟了半小时
He's already a half an hour late.
他会出现还是像上次那样爽约
He gonna show? Or that son of a bitch gonna stand her up like last time?
- 我煮咖啡  - 没时间了
- I'll make coffee. - I'm out of time, babe.
我的发夹不在沙发里
Mom, where are my barrettes? They're not in the couch.
戴蓝色那一个
Wear the blue ones.
我不想戴  颜色不配衬
I don't wanna wear the blue ones. They don't match.
- 浴室找过没有  - 找过了
- Did you check in your bathroom? - I checked everywhere.
- 我该怎办  - 去找
- Well, what do you want me to do? - Find them.
- 妈  留心  - 好了  宝贝
- Mom, pay attention. - All right, sweetie, all right. What?
- 爸爸会到来的  - 好啦
- Daddy's gonna be here. - Okay, he's gonna...
我来不及准备  我可不能迟到
I'm not gonna be ready. I can't be late.
- 你不会迟到的  - 我会迟到的
- You won't be late. - No, I will be late.
若一起找  爸到来前会找到
Okay. Before Daddy comes, we can find them if we look together.
- 没事的  宝贝  - 不
- It's all right, baby. It's all right. - No.
没事的
It's all right. It's all right.
我们一起找
We'll find them together, you and me. We'll find them together.
放心  他到来前我们会找到
Just relax. He won't come before we find them. I promise you.
给我添一杯
Hey. Give me another refill.
再添一杯
Now he wants a refill.
- 你叫什么  - 荣谷
- What's your name? - Waingro.
你是米高吧
You're Michael, huh?
你们常一起合作吗
You guys always work together?
经常合作
All the time.
- 合作无间吧  - 是的
- Real tight crew, huh? - Real tight.
若今次顺利  我会考虑再做
Yeah, if this works good, I'd consider going again, you know.
好的  别再说话  滑头
Yeah. Stop talking, okay, Slick?
- 他怎么样  - 百分百满意
- How's he doing? - A hundred percent.
很准时
Right on schedule.
威尼斯街右转
Made a right on Venice Boulevard.
- 我们离你一英里半  - 好的
- We're a mile and a half from you. - Okay.
越过行车快线  离你三百码
Just crossed over the number-one lane, 300 yards from you now.
- 准备  - 准备就绪
- Get set. - I am.
戴上面具
Put that on.
行动
Here we go.
有劫案  我们遇劫
Two eleven! Two eleven! We're being held up!
装甲车遇劫  已通知了警方
Two-eleven alarm. Armored car.
有三分钟
There's the call. Three minutes.
离开
Clear!
只剩八十秒
Eighty seconds left!
退后
Get back. Get back.
Get back!
滑头  他耳朵流血  听不到的
Hey, Slick, you see that shit coming out of their ears?
别胡来
They can't fucking hear you. Cool it.
找到了
I got it.
到手
Got it.
你要和我过不去
You had to fuck with me.
You wanna fuck with me?
快撤  你在做什么
Come on! What the fuck are you doing?
- 你干了什么  - 迫不得已  伙计
- What did you do? - I had to, man.
- 他作势要攻击  - 快走
- Guy was making a move. - Let's go.
我操你妈
Dumb motherfucker.
- 请退后  先生  - 我听到他们了
- Step back, please, sir. - I heard them.
一百六十万
A million six.
每元分四角  你可得六十四万
Forty cents on the dollar, 640,000 to you.
这是十五万的预支
Here's a 150 front money.
其余的两三天后付
Get you the rest in two, three days.
知道是谁拥有的吗
Know who owned these?
马莉堡股票及投资公司
Malibu Equity and Investments.
罗杰·宏山  在开曼群岛拥有银行
Roger Van Zant. Owns banks in the Caymans.
替国外毒贩洗钱  并负责投资事务
Runs investment portfolios for offshore drug money. Stuff like that.
- 那么  - 你偷了他的债券
- So? - So you ripped off his bearer bonds.
他买了保险
He's got insurance.
他可以获得百分百的保险赔偿
That's the point. He collects 100 percent from the insurance.
也许他向我们购回债券
He's a player. Maybe he buys his bonds back from us for 60 percent of their value.
六折价购回  再赚四成
And make 40 percent on top of the 100 percent.
债券卖给他  你可以再得到三十二万
Sell it back to him instead of going to the street. That's an extra 320,000 to you.
试试看
Try it on him.
- 祈素来电话  - 关于什么事
- Kelso called. - About what?
他找人参与买卖
A score he's putting out and wants you to look at.
我不需要  我自己有买卖
What do I need his score for? I got my own.
说钱无法追查而且超过千万元
Says it's clean and low eight figures.
- 明天九时  - 那儿发生了什么事
- 9 a.m. tomorrow. - What happened out there?
别问了
Don't ask.
找到救伤车了吗
Find the ambulance?
- 在四条街外遭弃掉  - 在二十二街的花店门口
- Dumped it four blocks from here. - 22nd Street between Figueroa and Flower.
纵火烧掉  枪和衣服化为灰烬
They torched it. Burned everything. The guns, clothes, everything.
调查员仍在现场工作
Investigators are still working the scene...
记者用直升机
They were airborne. Taped the last few seconds...
拍下几秒的黑白片
...of the black-and-whites doing demolition derby.
救伤车两星期前被偷
Stolen out of Fresno two weeks ago.
黄色车是前天在惠帝尔被偷
Yellow pickup truck out of whittier day before yesterday.
你负责此案  还是由分局调查
You taking this one, lieutenant, or does it stay in Division?
这一宗是便利店劫案吗
This look like gangbangers working the local 7-11 to you?
- 抢劫及凶杀组接手调查  - 全归你了
- Robbery-Homicide's taking it. Yeah. - All yours.
三名司机目击事发  只看见戴上面具的人
We got three motorists. All they saw were men with masks. They were distant.
那边的电视流浪汉距离现场很近
Console TV man over there however, he was closer.
他能认出任何人吗
He ID anybody?
他躲起来了  听到大部分对话
Well, he was hiding. He heard it mostly.
他们呢
Okay. What about them?
电视汉说这人在胡言乱语
Right. Now, according to TV man, this guy started mouthing off.
- 很聪明  - 有人把护卫叫作滑头
- Smart. - Yeah, somebody called a guard "Slick".
- 滑头  - 是的
- Slick? - Yeah.
我认为此人  想拿绑在足踝的枪
Now, this guy... I figure this guy went for that holdout piece, ankle holster, right?
由这儿
From here.
开枪
Bang. Bang. Bang, bang, bang.
子弹由这儿穿出
To his side.
这人看来好像是胸部中枪
This guy here has got what appears to be a double-tap entry wound to the sternum.
从头的伤势看似乎是近距离被杀
Tattooing around the head wound, scorched bone, close range.
很可能是处决
Probably executed.
一百六十万的债券被盗  他们没拿走现金
And it was a million six in bearer bonds, and they ignored the loose cash.
因为他们没时间  时间紧迫
Because they had no time, because they were on a clock.
他们知道警方何时会到达
Which means they knew our response time to a 2-11...
听警方广播  把车截停  进入
...had our air, immobilized it, entered...
及在三分钟内逃走
...escaped in under three minutes.
这是好地点  有良好逃走路线
It's a good spot here. We got good escape routes.
- 两条公路在四分之一英里以内  - 交通录影呢
- Two freeways within a quarter of a mile. - Traffic video camera?
可能给弄坏了  但还是查看一下
Probably disabled. Check it anyway.
你能认出手法吗
You recognize the M.O.?
手法  是职业劫匪所为
M.O. is that they're good.
他们杀死两名警卫  犯了一级谋杀罪
Once it escalated into a murder-one beef for all of them...
之后便不再迟疑
...after they killed the first two guards, they didn't hesitate...
杀了第三名  因为横竖也是犯罪
...popped guard number three because what difference does it make?
为何留下证人呢
Why leave a living witness?
他们会毫不迟疑  心狠手辣
Drop of a hat, these guys will rock 'n' roll.
定向炸药
The shape charge.
显示劫匪的技术是精通的
The shape charge indicates that they are technically proficient.
足以使他们在途中下手
Proficient enough to go in on the prowl.
我们要找偷值钱东西的劫匪
So let's start looking for recent high-line burglaries that have mystified us.
查滑头这个绰号
Run "Slick" as an alias to the FBI.
名单可能很长  但还是要查
You're gonna get the phone book. Do it anyway.
谁卖出债券
Who's moving the bearer bonds?
查惯常接赃者 你和我查古和陶
Check the usual fences. You and I will check Cusamano and Torena.
我要你查高士丹及艾化鲁  和鉴证科紧密合作
I want you to take Goldstein and Alfaro. Hang in with Forensics.
向炸弹组查问用的是什么炸药
From the bomb squad, I want the explosive.
若是罕见的  便可追查发售来源
If we're lucky, it's exotic. We can trace the sale.
你别伸手进那人的口袋
Get your hand out of that man's pocket, Rachel.
噢  云信
Oh, Vince.
有谁要吃批饼
Want some pie?
我要上厕所
Gotta go to the john.
他作势攻击  我要先下手为强
Look, I had to get it on, man. He was making a move. I had to get it on.
他那份在车上  我们的均分了
Split's in the car. I took out of ours evenly...
以便全数给他
...to make up for his full end.
因为我想立即分给他  打发这杂种
Because I wanna pay off and get rid of this motherfucker right now.
好的
Okay.
等一等
Hold it!
嘿
Hey.
- 其余的钱呢  - 时候不早了
- Where's the rest? - We're late.
你打扮得很漂亮  我想在这儿和你做爱
Ooh, you look too good to go out. I could just jump you right here.
- 钱呢  - 还给外围马的人了
- Where is it? - Uh, squared the bookies, baby.
几天后还会有钱  放心吧
There's more in a couple days, so don't sweat it. We really are late.
少胡说  你一定是说笑
Yeah, come on, you gotta be kidding me.
亲爱的  就为了区区八千元值得冒这个险吗
Honey, it ain't worth the risks you take for 8000.
危险和报酬要成正比
Like in risk versus reward, baby.
走吧  拿上你的外衣
Let's go. Get your coat.
无谓再说  你心智还没成熟
There is no point talking to you. All you are is a child growing older.
什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我们不像成年人那样有进步
It means we're not making forward progress like real grown-up adults, living our lives.
因为我嫁给了一个赌徒
I'm married to a gambling junkie who won't listen.
上车吧
Charlene, get in the fucking car.
我怎么可以这样下去的
What am I doing in this rat-bastard situation?
你不用  你离开这里时
You're not! What do you want from me? Leave the bankbook and car keys...
留下银行存折和车匙
...in the kitchen on your way out. Are we going, or am I going alone?
你留着吧  我只带多明一起走
You could keep that other crap but Dominick would go with me.
你别妄想
Don't you even think about...
陶·亚拔覆电话了
Yeah. Tell me Albert Torena called back.
- 陶·亚拔有给云信电话吗  - 没有
- Albert Torena call Vincent? - No.
没有  有报告
No. Report came in.
炸药是拆毁用的
The explosive was Dynex, linear-shaped charge used in demolition.
可在内华达  亚利桑拿  新墨西哥州买到
You can pick it up with a driver's license in Nevada, Arizona, New Mexico.
- 太普通  难以追查来源  - 那太好了
- Too common to trace a sale, Vincent. - Oh, that's wonderful.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
怎么了  你去了哪儿
What happened? Where you been?
工作
Work.
罗兰的父亲有来吗
Lauren's dad show up?
没来电话  没出现  我们等你直至十时半
Didn't call, didn't show. We waited for you till 10:30.
这人知道他女儿是怎样的吗
Now, does this guy have any idea what's going on with his kid?
我不知道
I don't know.
该死的混蛋
Fucking jerk.
她没事吧
Well, is she okay?
她整天在房内
She's been in her room all day.
她很难过  我亦不开心
So no, she's not okay. Neither am I.
我弄了晚餐  四小时前为我们煮了
Uh, I made dinner for us, four hours ago. Um...
我设法替我们保持一贯的情绪  你退却了
Every time I try to maintain a consistent mood between us, you withdraw.
在威尼斯大道旁边躺着三名死者  彩钿
I got three dead bodies on a sidewalk off Venice Boulevard, Justine.
对不起
I'm sorry...
若那可恶的鸡
...if the goddamn chicken...
给煮过了头
...got overcooked.
丹麦的七个人  是此案的关键被告
...seven men in Denmark, to a key defendant here.
- 你找到了吗  - 还没有
- Did you find it? - Not yet.
找到了
There it is.
过了这里  就在某一处
It's over here, somewhere.
- 室内设计呢  - 在后墙那边
- Interior design? - It's on the back wall.
- 要咖啡吗  - 好的
- Coffee, sir? - Please.
请把奶递给我
Will you pass the cream?
- 谢谢  - 你买了什么
- Thanks. - What did you get?
什么
What?
你在看什么书
What are you reading?
关于金属的书
Book about metals.
钛的应力折断
Stress Fractures in Titanium.
你干什么工作的
What kind of work you do?
你为何对我看什么书干什么工作感兴趣
Lady, why are you so interested in what I read or what I do?
我在店中看到过你
I've seen you in the store from time to time.
什么店
What store?
书店  我在那儿工作
Hennessey + Ingalls. I work there.
呃
Uh...
若你不想交谈  好的  抱歉打扰你了
If you don't wanna talk to me, it's okay. I'm sorry I bothered you.
我不想无礼  只是认不出你
I didn't mean to be rude. I didn't recognize you.
我是营业员  专门推销金属的  我叫尼尔
I work in metals. I'm a salesman. My name's Neil.
我叫伊荻
I'm Eady.
你喜欢在书店工作
You like working there?
是的
Sure.
我买书有折扣  亦有我行内的书
I get a discount and there's a whole section of books in my area.
是哪一行业
What area's that?
平面设计
Graphic design.
晚上设计信纸及商标
I do, um, letterheads and logotypes at night...
白天在书店工作直至能藉此谋生
...and the store's a day job till I get enough going.
你为谁设计呢
Who do you do that for?
餐厅
Uh, a restaurant.
我设计他们的餐牌  以及
I did their menus, and, um...
为小唱片公司设计
...a small, uh, record label.
镭射唱片封套  目前已设计了两张
CDs. I've done two so far.
你上学校受训吗
You go to school for that?
是的
Heh, yeah.
- 我念过巴桑学校  - 在哪儿
- Yeah, I went to Parsons. - Where's that?
纽约市
New York City.
你在这儿住了多久
How long you been out here?
约一年
About a year.
喜欢这儿吗
You like it?
不算喜欢  我为工作才来这儿
Not really. I'm mostly here for the work.
- 你住在附近吗  - 不
- Live in this neighborhood? - Ah, no...
我住在日落广场上面山上
...I live, um, kind of above Sunset Plaza.
租住一所小房子
It's actually kind of... It's a little house that I rent.
颇为破旧  但景观极佳
And it's just kind of run-down, but a beautiful, beautiful view.
你呢
What about you?
- 我住在这儿  - 很有趣
- I live up here. - That's very funny.
你的家人原本从哪儿来
So where's your family from originally?
嗯
Um...
是苏格兰及爱尔兰裔
I'm Scotch-Irish.
一七零零年末期移居美国东南部
They, um, emigrated to Appalachia in the late 1700s.
你从哪儿来
Where are you from?
三藩市湾区
The Bay Area.
家人在那儿
Are your folks there?
母亲很久前死了  我父亲  我也不知他在哪儿
Uh, my mother died a long time ago, and my father, I don't know where he is.
我有个兄弟
Got a brother somewhere.
你的家人关系很紧密吧
You have a tight family. I can tell.
- 是的  - 是吗
- Yep. - Right?
你说得对
You're right.
是啊
Yeah...
灯火通明的城市
City of lights.
在菲济  有一种会发光的海藻  每年浮出水面一次
In Fiji, they have these iridescent algae. They come out once a year in the water.
这城市的灯正是如此
That's what it looks like out there.
你到过菲济
You been there?
没有  我终有一天会去
No, I'm going there someday.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你常旅游
You travel a lot?
- 是的  - 旅游使你寂寞
- Yeah. - Traveling makes you lonely?
我一个人  可我并不寂寞
I... I'm alone. I am not lonely.
你呢
You?
很寂寞
I get lonely.
亚拔
Albert!
- 糟了  - 亚拔
- Shit. - Albert.
你为何来这儿
Vincent, what you doing coming here, man?
你疯了吗
You crazy? This ain't Disneyland.
你该回覆我电话的  你去了哪儿
You were supposed to get back to me last night, Albert. Where the fuck you been?
- 我无法脱身  - 我们侵犯他的民权吧
- I couldn't break free, Vincent. You know. - Let's violate his ass right now.
我帮你忙  你却不帮我  是这样吗
I do for you, you don't do for me, is that it?
我整晚外出
Vincent, man, I swear, I was out all night, man.
为你刺探消息
I'm hitting like one of them flamingo-matador guys.
此事和我无关
Flamingo? That's got nothing to do with me.
我顺利为你找到线索
I was cutting it real smooth. I'm generating leads and shit for you.
- 我很棒  - 你胡说
- I'm a dancer, man. You know. - Bullshit.
我传呼你一整天  我讨厌这样做
I paged your ass all day. I can't stand paging.
你又再是瘾君子  注射毒品
You're a speed freak, jacking methamphetamine again.
我有滥用药物的问题  心领吧
Where is your empathy, brother? It's a substance-abuse problem.
我昨天对你心领
Empathy was yesterday.
你今天却浪费我时间
Today you're wasting my motherfucking time.
- 听着  - 你恋爱了吗
- Vincent, man, look... - Did you fall in love?
你是否恋爱和到别处去啦
Come on. Did you fall in love last night and you went off somewhere?
- 云信  - 我会接受这解释
- Vincent... - Just tell me that. I'll settle for it.
- 我会信的  - 云信
- I'll buy that. - Vincent.
把消息告诉我
Give me all you got!
- 云信  - 把资料对我说
- Vincent... - Give me all you got!
我发誓  我哥哥里察会跟你说
I swear, man, my brother, man. My brother Richard's gonna talk to you.
你是说里察吗
I heard "Richard"?
- 他会和你说的  - 里察
- He's gonna talk to you. - Richard?
- 里察  - 里察
- Richard. - Richard.
- 他今晚会见你  - 他在这儿
- He's gonna meet you, I swear, tonight. - He's not here, is he?
- 不  他会见你  - 现在不行吗
- No, he's gonna meet you tonight. - Tonight? What happened to now?
我恳求他  因为我知道你今早会到来
I... I... I implored him because I knew you was coming this a.m.
- 胡说  - 没有  我发誓
- This is a bunch of bullshit. - No, no, I swear.
他不肯的  因为他在凤凰城
He said no because he in Phoenix.
- 啊  - 我发誓
- Ahh. - But this, man, I swear... I swear, man.
我到了凤凰城后
By the time I get to Phoenix,
他会起程
He'll be risin',
可能留下字条  贴在门上
He'll probably leave a note right on the door
我只能令他今晚见你
Tonight's the best I can do for you, man.
今晚在艾华瓦度街BJ夜总会
You know? He'll meet you at BJ's on Alvarado...
凌晨二时  你去吧
...at 2 a.m. Be there.
你亦要到
You be there too.
不行  我有事要办
Vincent, I can't be there, man. I got things to do, Vincent.
- 我有事办  要到别处  - 嘿
- I got things to do, places to be. I got... - Hey, hey, hey.
你要去
Be there.
你别浪费我的时间
Don't waste my motherfucking time!
是什么买卖
What is it?
是银行
It's a bank.
星期四会存钱以便分发各分行
It depos cash on Thursday for distribution to all the other branches...
应付星期五支付薪金的支票
...to cover Friday payroll checks.
总行夹万内星期四总放满现钞
So on Thursdays, the command branch has got a full whack.
- 在途中下手还是劫银行  - 由正门进入
- On the prowl or strong? - Strong. Through the front door.
有多少人
How many guys?
连司机四人  走进银行  得手便走
Four, or three plus a driver. Walk in, knock them over, walk out.
你要先拿十万
And you want a 100,000 advance...
事成后分一成
...against a 10-percent cut for that?
听似是西部牛仔劫银行  他们按动警钟
Sounds like an address to a cowboy score. They hit the holdup alarms...
我得在之前离去
...I gotta get out before the cops show. What is that?
他们可按动三个遇劫警钟
They hit three holdup alarm systems.
两个一般警钟和一个蜂窝式的
Two telco and a cellular.
但讯号无法传送出去  因为
See, but the signals aren't going anywhere because...
之前一晚  你潜进银行  破坏警报系统的电脑
See, the night before, you cut in and trick out the alarm-system computer...
使电脑及录影装置在你下手前二十分钟关掉
...to turn itself and the video recorders off 20 minutes before you walk in the door.
你有建筑及电子蓝图吗
Architectural, electrical-engineering plans?
我有  我建造电脑板  直驳中央处理器
I got all that. Schematics, got the boards already built. They go straight into the CPU.
估计可有多少钱
What's the estimate?
一千两百一十万到一千两百二十万
12.1, 12.2 million.
我会参加
You're on.
恭喜
Congratulations.
我告诉你如何估计会有这笔钱
And to give you a little idea of where my estimates come from, this is a printout...
没人知道货是你的
Nobody knew the merch was yours.
我让你得保险全数
Be that as it may, my way you get 100 percent from the insurance company...
赔偿以六成价  把债券回购
...and take the bonds from us at 60 cents on the dollar...
你可多赚四成
...and make yourself another 40 percent.
行动全无损失  我们均可赚大钱
Your operation doesn't skip a beat. Everybody makes out.
我同意
Sure, you got a deal.
好  若大家不喜欢便没得益
Good, because there's no percentage if everyone gets their underwear in a twist.
要你的人给我电话  安排会面
Yeah, so you have your man call me and we'll set the meet.
行啊  可以
Yeah, okay.
高兴和你通电话
Nice talking to you.
你要和他们交易吗
You gonna deal with these guys?
江湖上可接受我偷自己的东西吗
So word's out on the street it's okay to steal my stuff.
我会杀了这班浑蛋
I'm gonna kill the sons of bitches.
命哈利给我加那利群岛的试算纸
Have Harry bring me the spreadsheets for Canary Islands' offshore.
这些不是估计  是实在数字
That's not really an estimate. Those are exact figures.
我印出银行过去两月的现金帐
I have a printout of the, uh, cash flow of the bank for the past two months.
- 资料怎么得来的  - 送上门的
- How'd you get this information? - Just comes to you.
资料府拾皆是
This stuff just flies through the air.
到处传送  只需加以掌握便行
They send information out and it's beamed out all over the place.
我懂得掌握
All you have to do is know how to grab it. See, I know how to grab it.
这是我们要的  一千三百九十万
Um... Okay, here we go. Thirteen-point-nine million.
- 我同意了  - 好啊
- I bought it. - Good.
我没说错吧
What did I tell you?
拿着
Here.
同意了  联络宏山  准备收钱吧
We're on. Call Van Zant, collect the money.
- 他怎么样  - 他是生意人
- How is he? - He's a businessman.
好吧
Okay.
- 鳄梨  - 鳄梨
- Avocado. - Avocado.
- 喂  - 是我
- Hello? - Yeah, hello.
基斯在我家中
Chris is at my place.
- 怎么了  - 夫妻的争吵
- What's wrong? - Husband-and-wife stuff.
我让他睡醒再算
I'll let him sleep it off here.
你怎么了
What happened to you?
- 你何时买家具  - 我有时间便买
- When you gonna get some furniture? - When I get around to it.
莎莲要离开我
Charlene's gonna leave me.
为什么
Why?
我无好好供养她
Not enough steaks in the freezer.
我们做买卖还不够钱吗
With everything we've been doing?
赌场及赌球赛使我身无分文
Vegas and the Super Bowl cleaned me out.
- 你何时会结婚  - 有时间再算
- When you gonna get an old lady? - When I get around to it.
你有外遇吗
You got something else on the side?
没固定的
Nothing regular.
她有外遇吗
She got something else on the side?
- 没有  - 你肯定吗
- No. - You sure?
肯定
Yeah, I'm sure.
我不知你做什么
I don't know what you're doing.
如占美说
Remember Jimmy MacAwain on the yard used to say:
你想当罪犯吗
You wanna be making moves on the street?
要无牵挂  生活中不能有任何牵挂
Have no attachments. Allow nothing to be in your life...
风声紧时便可抛下一切
...that you cannot walk out on in 30 seconds flat...
一走了之
...if you spot the heat around the corner.
记得吗
Remember that?
她是我一生中最重要的
For me, the sun rises and sets with her, man.
是吗
Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
我们从宏山那儿拿到钱
Today we take delivery of cash from Van Zant...
然后为劫银行的事存钱给祈素
...then I drop our deposit on Kelso for this bank.
什么银行
Bank? What bank?
这白金的事如何  快成事了
What about the platinum thing? It's ready to fall.
那亦会进行  然后再劫银行
That goes too, then the bank.
- 要吃早餐吗  - 好啊
- You want some breakfast? - Yeah.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah, sugar.
耶
Yeah.
- 是真的  - 好吧
- For real. - Okay.
我会好好的做
Gonna do good.
再见
I'll see you later.
你是索伦戈吗  我是当·毕顿
You Solenko? I'm Don Breedan.
假释官告诉我  你会有工作给我
Grierson, my parole officer, told me to come by here and see if you had a job for me.
- 你对工作娴熟吗  - 我烧烤很出色的
- You're familiar with this kind of operation? - Yeah, man. I'm a great grill man.
好  你洗抹厕所  洗碗碟
Good. Good for you. Here, you'll mop the toilets, hit the dishwasher...
收拾桌子
...bus tables and empty the garbage too.
你若烦我  我就举报你藏毒酗酒或偷窃
Give me a hard time, I'll report you loaded, drunk or stealing.
很快举报你违反假释条例
And I will violate you back so fast your head will spin.
你给我薪金的百分之二十五作为回佣
Twenty-five percent of your take-home kicks back to me.
是规矩  问假释官吧
Rules of the game. Call Grierson, check it out.
后面更衣
Change in the back.
你还等什么
Well, what are you waiting for?
马莉堡股票及投资
Malibu Equity and Investments.
- 罗杰·宏山  - 请稍等
- Yeah, Roger Van Zant. - Please hold.
我是罗杰·宏山
Yeah, this is Roger Van Zant.
我该有一些东西的
I'm supposed to collect something.
把你的号码告诉我  会有人给你回覆电话
Give me your number, and somebody will call you right back from a different line.
818-133-6089
818-133-6089.
喂
Yep.
我有个包裹给你
I got a package for you.
明午二时半露天影院见
There's a drive-in on Centinela. 02:30 tomorrow.
只派一人单独前来
Okay, just send one man, alone.
- 那人是谁  - 无名小卒
- Who was that guy? - Nobody.
那人是谁
Who the...? Who...? Who was that guy?
- 无名小卒  - 我要知道他是谁
- He's nobody. - I gotta know who he is. Who is he?
- 他是无名小卒  - 听着
- He's nobody, Neil. - Listen, you...
他是赌城合法酒类营业员
He's a legit liquor wholesaler from Las Vegas.
- 马·亚伦  - 基斯会与你和解
- Alan Marciano. - Chris is gonna straighten it up with you.
- 太迟了  我讨厌他  - 闭嘴
- It's too late. I'm sick of it. I'm sick of it! - Shut up!
你再给基斯一次机会
Here's the deal. You'll give Chris one last shot.
若他再犯错  我会资助你找地方住
After that, he fucks up, then I will finance setting you up myself...
住哪里都行
...on my own, anywhere you want.
多明也会跟着你  我言出必行
Dominick will go with you. And my word counts.
但现在  你得再给他一次机会
But right now, you will give him the chance.
清洗一下  回家去
Clean up. Go home.
交出你的钱
Give me all your money.
你会因此而没命的
One day you gonna get smoked with that shit.
杀我的不会是你
Ain't gonna be you, fool.
他一个人来
- He's coming in alone. Send him through. - Yeah, got it.
云信
Vincent, hey, man.
这是我哥哥里察  云信
Vincent. This is my brother, Richard. Richard, Vincent.
- 里察  - 没关系
- Richard. - Yo, it's all right.
你有何消息告诉我
What have you got for me?
谈正题前
Before we even get into that...
沙滩附近有人偷车
...there's this crew ripping rides all along the beach areas, all right?
在汽车装饰店后
Now, the back of a trim shop on Irvine...
若周末有人前去那儿
...if somebody was to pay a little visit this weekend...
会找到一辆名贵跑车
...they might find two Turbos and a 911 Slope.
你参加赛车吗
You're looking to rid yourself of your competition.
我是个好市民
Eh, I'm a good citizen.
我才不信  你有事要告诉我
I'm Donald Duck. So you got something to tell me or what?
你听着  朋友
Check this out, coz.
我怎知若我说出你所想知的事
How do I know if I tell you what you need to know...
你会做我所想做的事
...you're gonna do what the fuck I need to get done?
里察  韩很可靠的
Richard, man, Hanna is straight up, man. We do business all the time.
杂种  我不是你的朋友
I ain't your coz, you rat motherfucker.
你知道我说得出做得到  但我要先听你有什么话要说
And you know because I say so after I hear what the fuck you gotta tell me.
我操  明白吗
Look here, man. You understand what I'm saying?
我说出来会没命的
I can get killed for telling you this shit.
你溜狗时亦会没命
Or you're gonna get killed walking your doggie.
好吧
All right.
我和这人在狱中相识
There's this cat I was locked up with in Folsom.
服刑两三年  他出狱后我碰上他
Did a couple, two, three years. He got out and I ran into him.
那又怎样
And so?
他是坐言起行的人
He's a big fiend for action.
若他不说  我便不会去想  可是
Now, if he'd have said nothing, I'd have thought nothing...
他不断的对我说他什么也没做
...but he goes on and on, running down to me how he ain't been doing nothing...
而且也没事发生  等等等等
...and nothing's been going on, and all this bullshit.
那时我便知道  这人参与了不法行为
So right then and there I know this cat's got something going down.
而且是大案
Pretty fucking great.
亚拔  你怎么回事
Albert, what's wrong with you?
你要我来这里  浪费我的时间
You drag me here, waste my time like this.
你见过坐过牢的人
You saw a guy on the street who's an ex-con?
- 是的  - 那么我很喜出望外
- That's right. - Well, I am over-fucking-whelmed.
你想为此拿警章吗
What do you want for that, a Junior G-man badge?
你会查跑车的事吗
You gonna make the call on them Porsches or what?
他是说笑吗
Is he kidding me?
我告诉你  滑头从不说笑
I'm telling you, this Slick is no joke.
他为人紧张
You know what I'm saying?
- 你说什么  - 什么
- Say what? Say what? - What?
- 滑头  那是什么意思  - 他常叫别人为滑头
- You said, "Slick". What does that mean? - Slick. That's what he calls people, "Slick".
把他的事告诉我
And tell me about him.
他约六英尺高  有许多监狱的纹身
About 6 feet tall, lot of jailhouse tats.
这儿刺有一头大孔雀
Got a big-ass peacock right here.
他叫什么名字
What's his name?
姓查
Cheritto.
查·米高
Michael Cheritto.
自一九七六年起被捕三十三次
33 busts since 1976.
十一次持械行劫  三次给定罪
Eleven for armed robbery, three convictions.
判刑三至五年  在纽约服刑两年
Two out of a three-to-five-year beef in Attica. Three years in Marion.
中西部服刑三年  因误杀罪在霍森监狱服刑五年
Five years in Folsom off a knock-back to involuntary manslaughter.
- 他的案底达两英寸厚  - 很好
- Jacket's 2 inches thick. - Okay.
- 现在还有谁有听  -  泽加和我  以及舒华兹
- Who do I have there now? - Drucker and me, boss. And Schwartz.
通知特别调查科
Tell SIS I want full surveillance.
我要二十四小时监视他
That's 24 hours. Round the clock, day and night.
不断监视跟踪他  监听他的汽车和房子
We never close. Open seven days a week. Bug the car, the house, the work.
一举一动
When he moves or sits, like in a restaurant...
和谁人一起也拍照
...I want pictures of who he moves and sits with.
调查他们  若有案底便跟踪他们
Then run makes on them. They got jackets, I wanna see who they move and sit with.
我要明天便执行
I want it up and running by tomorrow night.
- 把手放在我看得到的地方  - 什么
- Put your hands where I can see them. - What?
- 把手放在我看得到的地方  - 好的
- Put your hands where I can see them. - All right.
我会告诉你做什么  以及怎样去做
I tell you what to do, I tell you how to do it.
现在  只用你的右手  只准右手
Now, with your right hand only, your right hand only...
把包裹拿出来  扔过来
...take the package and throw it in here.
你右面  后面有人
Fuck. Behind you. On the right.
罗杰·宏山
Yeah, Roger Van Zant?
- 你是谁  - 你知道我是谁
- Yeah, who's this? - You know who this is.
我知道
Yes, I do. Yes, I do.
我派人送包裹  他没来电话  一切妥当吧
I sent a guy to deliver the package. He didn't call. Is everything right?
我告诉你  忘记那笔钱
Tell you what, forget the money.
- 什么  - 忘记那笔钱
- What? - Forget the money.
呃
Wh...
数目不少  你究竟想做什么  忘记那笔钱是什么意思
It's a lot of money. What are you doing? What do you mean, forget the money?
我在做什么  我在对着话筒自说自话
What am I doing? I'm talking to an empty telephone...
我不明白
I don't understand.
因为电话的另一端是个死人
...because there is a dead man on the other end of this fucking line.
天呐
Oh, my.
- 你喜欢吗  - 看我的戒指
- Do you like it? - Look at my ring.
真漂亮
Wow.
你知道的吗
Did you know about this? It's so beautiful.
你疯了
You are insane.
喜欢吗
Do you like it?
- 很漂亮  - 是啊  很漂亮
- It's beautiful. - Yeah, it's pretty good.
- 别问他哪儿得来的  - 对  别问
- Just don't ask him where he got it. - Yeah, that's right.
你长大后想做什么  宝贝
What do you wanna be when you grow up, honey?
我不知道
I don't know.
她不知道  像我一样  我亦不知道
She doesn't know. Just like me. I don't know either.
你好
Hello?
嗨  是我
Hi, it's me.
我在想你是否会来电话
Hey. I was wondering if you'd call.
我很忙  我能见你吗
I've been busy. Can I see you?
我害怕那只是一夜情
I was afraid that was just the one night, you know?
对我来说不是
No, not for me, it wasn't.
我也不是
Yeah, me neither.
我能来吗
Can I fall by?
- 可以  - 好的  一会儿见
- Yeah. - Okay, I'll see you in a little bit.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚安
Good night.
可恶的会议
Goddamn convention.
- 哪一个是滑头  - 魁悟的那个
- Which one's Slick? - The wide one.
有两个监视器
Got two transmitters.
分别在防火板及轮内
One's in the wheel well, backup's in the firewall.
是我们的车
Okay, get ready.
- 跟尼尔道别了吗  - 晚安
- Did you say good night to Neil? - Good night.
金发的是施基斯  特别调查组已派人跟踪他
One with the blond hair is Chris Shiherlis. SIS has got a revolving tail...
并监听了他家的座机
...and hung a wire on the house phone.
查把车三次驶过贵重金属库
Cheritto's cruised the precious-metals depository three times.
白金银和一些金条
Platinum, silver, and some bullion.
森美和我认为是他们下一目标
Sammy and I think that's gonna be their next score.
那独行者是谁
Who's the loner?
我们第一次见他  还没开始跟踪他
First time we're seeing him. We're not on him yet.
立即开始吧
Well, get on it.
好的
Okay.
他们下次做案得手走出大门时
When these guys walk out the door of whatever score they're gonna take next...
一定会大感惊愕
...they're gonna have the surprise of a lifetime.
我要走了
Hey, baby. Time to go.
我令你很开心吧
I showed you a good time, didn't I?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
你很棒  你不错
You fly. You cool.
你骗我  我看得出别人骗我
You're lying to me. I can always tell when people lie to me.
我没说谎  你很勇猛
Mm, I ain't lying. You a hot dog.
是出色的骑士
A regular rodeo rider.
是我试过最精彩的性行为
And this was the monster fuck of my young life.
我现在得回到街上去
Now I got to get my ass street side, sugar.
你没有老实的作风
You don't have a truth-telling style.
- 你说什么  - 你不知道是什么回事
- What are you talking about? - You don't know what this is.
是死神来探望你
The Grim Reaper's visiting with you.
你去了哪儿
Where you been?
塘鹅弯的特别收容所
SHU at Pelican Bay.
以及霍森监狱B座
New Folsom, B-wing.
我是一个想做大买卖的人
I am a cowboy looking for anything heavy.
比利说来找你
Billy Ricketts said come see you.
因此我到来
That is why I am here.
你为何不
Why don't you...?
你为何不打电话给这人
Why don't you call this guy?
他经常招人入伙
This guy's always putting guys on.
谢谢  兄弟
Thank you, brother.
- 我要请你喝酒吗  - 请我喝酒
- I'll buy you a drink? - Buy me a drink.
- 笑什么  - 没什么
- What's so funny? - Nothing.
- 这家伙  真够傻的  - 你在责备我吗
- It's really dumb. - Something smells negligent.
你们天生一对
You two are perfect for each other. How did you meet?
我念小学时认识一人
I knew this guy in, uh, grade school.
他叫罗尔  什么的
He was named Raoul, uh... Whatever.
他可以把手指彼此屈折起来
Anyway, the guy could take his fingers and fold them over, one over the other.
他可以把眼睑向外翻
Then he'd turn his eyelids inside out...
我禁不住对你上下其手  是真的
I can't keep my hands off you, and that's the truth.
你吸引人的地方在于你那兽性的方式
That's what's so wonderful about you, in that bestial sort of way.
女人
Woman.
这最好是轰动的大事
This better be earth-shattering.
为罗尔干杯
That's what she tells us. To Raoul.
- 罗尔  - 敬罗尔
- Raoul. - To Raoul.
我是韩·云信
Yeah, Vincent Hanna.
发现她时是这样的
Here's how we found her.
- 她有多大  - 十六七岁
- How old? - Sixteen, seventeen.
在此约六小时
Been here about six hours.
她怎么死的
How'd she die, Rachel?
头部遭受重击  大脑血肿
Beat her head in, same as the others. Cerebral hematoma.
那是谁
Who's that?
- 我猜是死者母亲及兄弟  - 他们为何到来
- Mother and siblings, I guess. - What the hell they doing here?
酒店内有人认识死者  就通知了家人
Because it's fucked up. Somebody inside knew the girl and called the family.
让我看看
Okay, let's go.
不错
That's nice.
直觉告诉我  化验精液是同一人
When I run a DNA check on the semen, my intuition says it's coming up the same guy.
是连环谋杀案  要由你着手调查
So it's a series, and ending up in your court.
- 警长有头绪吗  - 还没有
- Sheriff's Homicide getting anywhere? - Not yet.
- 拦住她  - 放开我
- Get her. - Get off me. Get off me.
噢
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
- 天啊  - 冷静
- Oh, my God. - Hold it, hold it.
- 她在哪儿  - 冷静
- Where is she? - Easy, easy, easy.
别这样
Please. Please, come on.
- 没事的  - 谁干的
- It's okay. It's okay. - Who did this?
我的女儿呢  她在哪儿
Where's my baby? Where is she?
我要知道是什么回事
I need to know what happened.
我猜是很轰动吧
I guess the Earth shattered.
你为何不让博高送你回家
So why didn't you let Bosko take you home?
我不想扫他们的兴  有什么事
I didn't wanna ruin their night too. What was it?
你不想知道的
You don't wanna know.
我想知道你为何扳起脸孔
I'd like to know what's behind that grim look.
我不能透露  你是知道的
I don't do that. You know it. Let's go. Come on.
你从没告诉我  我会摒诸事外
You never told me I'd be excluded.
我告诉你  我们在一起时  你要和我分享
I told you when we hooked up, baby, that you were gonna have to share me...
世上所有的丑行及丑恶的人
...with all the bad people and all the ugly events on this planet.
我同意接受分享  因为我爱你
And I bought into that sharing because I love you.
即使你发胖  秃头  没钱  我仍会爱你
I love you fat, bald, money, no money, driving a bus. I don't care.
但你一定要存在
But you have got to be present like a normal guy some of the time.
那是分享  这不是分享  是残余的
That's sharing. This is not sharing, this is leftovers.
明白了  我该回家  然后我该说
Oh, I see. What I should do is come home and say:
宝贝儿  你知道吗  我今天走进一所房子
Hi, honey, guess what? I walked into this house today...
这瘾君子用微波炉煮熟了孩子
...where this junkie asshole just fried his baby in a microwave...
就因为他的哭声太吵闹  我和你分享吧
...because it was crying too loud, so let me share that with you.
让我们分享此事  而在分享时
Come on, let's share that, and in sharing it...
我们会宣泄一切可怕的事件  对吗
...we'll somehow cathartically dispel all that heinous shit, right?
错  你知道为什么吗
Wrong. You know why?
你喜欢正常的做法
Because you prefer the normal routine.
我们做爱  你不说话
We fuck, then you lose the power of speech.
我得保持我的痛苦
Because I gotta hold on to my angst.
我保存它  因为我需要藉此提高警觉
I preserve it, because I need it. It keeps me sharp, on the edge.
我要这样做
Where I gotta be.
你不是和我同住
You don't live with me.
你和死者的残骸同住
You live among the remains of dead people.
你筛选碎片  在地势找线索
You read the terrain.
你找寻死亡的迹象
You search for signs of passing...
找猎物的气味
...for the scent of your prey...
然后追捕他们
...and then you hunt them down.
这是你唯一投入的事
That's the only thing you're committed to.
其余的是你留下的烂摊子
The rest is the mess you leave as you pass through.
我不明白为何不能离开你
What I don't understand is why I can't cut loose of you.
嘿  莉莉安
Hey. Miss Lillian.
走吧  宝贝
Let's go, baby.
我见过经理  那是老板吗
I met the manager. Is that the boss?
我为他每天所做的事而坐牢
I did time for what that motherfucker does every day.
你可忍受直至找到新工作吗
Baby, can you just handle it till we find you something new?
你可以吗
Can you do that?
更难忍受的我亦捱过
Ain't a hard time been invented that I cannot handle.
你为何和我在一起  莉莉安
What you hanging with me for, Lillian?
因为你令我感骄傲
Because I'm proud of you.
你以我为荣吗
You're proud of me?
为什么
What the hell you proud of me for?
回家吧
Come on home.
- 你在哪儿做什么  - 我滑雪
- What were you doing there? - I was skiing.
我想滑雪
I was trying to ski.
那儿的人会这样做  去滑雪
That's what people do there. You go skiing...
可结识别人
...and you meet people.
你想开心一下
You try to have a good time.
- 你开心吗  - 不
- Did you have a good time? - No.
为什么
Why not?
我不擅交际
I'm not good at meeting people.
你认识了我
You met me.
我没仔细想  事情便发生了
Well, that happened without my thinking about it.
可能是因为这样
Which is why, probably.
不  是因为你是个好女人
No, it's because you were fine.
伊荻
Eady.
和我到外地去
Take off with me for a while.
- 去哪儿  - 新西兰
- Where? - New Zealand.
何时
When?
我不能和你同去  但你可以在那儿与我会和
I have to go separate, but you could meet me there.
但我的工作
But my job, my...
我有钱  你不用工作  你可以在那儿开设计公司
I got money. You don't need money. You could set up a studio, do work there.
- 我不知道  - 还要知道什么
- I don't know. - What's there to know?
你结婚了吗
Are you married?
- 什么  - 你来了又走了
- What? - You come and go...
我才没有结婚
The last thing I am is married.
我的生活正在走下坡
I'm a needle starting at zero going the other way, a double blank.
可是  突然
Then, all of a sudden...
出现了你这样的人
...someone like you comes along.
- 你不了解我  - 足够了解了
- You don't know me, Neil. - I know enough.
跟我走
Come with me.
有何不妥
What's wrong, baby?
没什么  一切妥当  你会去吗
Nothing's wrong. Everything's right. Will you go?
会
Yeah.
好
Good.
- 嘿  亲爱的  - 嗨
- Hey, sweetie. - Hi.
你忘记妈妈会接你吗
What happened? You forget your mom was picking you up?
不是
No.
怎么回事
So, what's going on?
我想独自一人待着
I felt like being alone.
好吧  上车  我送你回家
Okay. Come on, I'll drive you home.
- 嘿  麦克  - 嘿  罗兰
- Hey, Mike. - Hey, Lauren.
有何动静
What's happening?
长官
Lieutenant. Sir.
杰克逊警长想知道有何动静
Captain Jackson wants to know what's going on.
没动静  不要用无线电
Nothing's going on. Stay off the air.
杰克逊
Jackson's a...
好技术
Technique.
芝麻开门
Open sesame. Right there.
就是他
There he goes.
- 我们走吧  - 我快完事了
- We walk. - I'm right there.
我们撤  即刻  快点
We walk! Now! Come on.
他听到了
He's heard it.
他们来了
Heads up.
- 有一个出来了  - 等一等  队长
- One's coming out. - Hold it, captain.
- 云信  他没带走任何东西  - 是的  我看见了
- Vincent, he's not carrying anything. - Yeah, I see.
- 行动  - 得让我上司批准
- Here we go. - Not till my boss says so.
云信  他们没拿东西
Vincent, both of them are not carrying anything.
- 让他们走  - 什么意思
- Okay, let them go. - What do you mean?
我们可以拘捕他们
We can take them...
控以何罪  非法闯入吗
What are you gonna take them on? Breaking and entry?
他们没偷东西  明白吗
They didn't steal anything. Don't you get it?
行为不检
It gets knocked back to some misdemeanor...
他们坐牢半年便出狱  不行
...they do six months and they're out. No fucking way.
我可不想接受批评  他们不能走
I'm not taking the heat from my boss. They're not walking.
他们会走  今次行动由我指挥
That's exactly what they're gonna do. They're gonna walk. This is my operation.
我的战略指挥凌驾你的职级
I have tactical command that supersedes your rank.
他们会离去  你会让他们走
They will walk away and you will let them. Fuck.
继续工作
Back to work.
洛城警方  密探  警方从何而来
L.A.P.D. Gee, what? Where the fuck did this heat come from?
他们或许知道那儿会被劫
Maybe it's the score they were onto.
但不知道是我们  因为那儿以前曾遇劫
The place, not us. Because it's been hit a couple of times, you know.
假设他们知道我们的电话  住所
Assume they got our phones, assume they got our houses...
知道我们在此集会
...assume they got us right here, right now as we sit.
假设他们知道一切
Everything. Assume it all.
我们如何付劫银行的上期
How we gonna buy the bank package from Kelso?
- 我先垫付吧  - 宏山呢
- I'll front that. That's not a problem. - What happens to Van Zant?
警方现在正追查我们  你想和他开战吗
With the heat we got, do you wanna play World War II in the streets with Van Zant?
不  我想拿七十五万
No, I want my 750. And he gets a pass?
我比你更想杀了宏山  他太放肆了
I got more motivation to whack Van Zant than either of you. He is a fucking luxury.
问题是  我们劫银行  还是离去
Our problem is, take the bank or split right now?
不要回家收拾东西
Do not go home, do not pack, nothing.
三十秒后我们会各走各路
Thirty seconds flat from now, we are gone on our separate ways.
就这样
That's it.
基斯
Chris.
值得冒险劫银行
The bank is worth the risk.
我需要钱
I need it, brother.
我认为我们该留下来劫银行
We should stay and take it down. That's where I come out.
你做什么我亦跟随
I roll with you, Neil. Whatever. Whatever.
但今次不行  米高  你要自行决定
No, not on this one, Michael. On this one, you're on your own.
这是最好的做法吗
You figure this is the best thing to do?
是最好的做法吗
This is the best thing to do?
事后我有打算  值得为这笔钱坐牢
I got plans. I'm going away after. So for me the reward is maybe worth the stretch.
但绮玲很照顾你  你有许多钱
But Elaine takes good care of you. You got plenty put away.
你有物业
You got T-bonds, real estate.
若我是你  便不参与今次行动
If I were you, I would be smart. I would cut loose of this.
对我来说  行动使生活更刺激
Well, you know, for me, the action is the juice.
我参加
I'm in.
你呢
You too?
我会
Yeah, sure.
动手吧
Let's go.
去他们的  行动吧
Fuck them, let's do it.
那好  我们有许多事要做
All right, let's go. We got a lot of work to do.
- 你们不能进去  - 查查这个
- You can't go in there. - Watch this.
- 抱歉  等等  - 提姆  我回头再给你打电话
- Excuse me. That... - Tim, I gotta call you back.
你得提前预约
You have to have an appointment.
- 我能帮助你吗  - 你是马·亚伦吗
- Can I help you? - Are you Alan Marciano?
- 是我  你他妈是谁  - 我是谁
- Yeah, and who the fuck are you? - Who am I?
- 嘿  - 洛城警局的韩·云信探长
- Hey. Hey. - Lieutenant Vincent Hanna, L.A.P.D.
这里是赌城拉斯维加斯  不在你的管辖范围
L.A.? This is Las Vegas. You don't even have jurisdiction here.
你知道在惹恼谁吗
Hey. Hey, I don't know who the fuck you guys think you're pushing around...
- 我认识这儿的大人物  - 我可以让赌城警方拘押你
- ...but I know people here, okay? - Las Vegas P.D. takes you into custody.
你会因从北卡罗来纳走私香烟
You are extradited to Newark on a New Jersey warrant...
而被引渡回纽华克
...for smuggling cigarettes up from North Carolina three years ago...
或是你可和我们合作
...or you go to work for us.
简单明快
Cut and dried.
- 就是这样  - 妈的
- That is it. - Oh, shit.
施·莎莲
Charlene Shiherlis.
- 谁  - 谁
- Who? - Who?
谁  你是猫头鹰吗
Who? What are you, a fucking owl?
和你在电话中淫声浪语的女子
The lady you been talking dirty to on the telephone every day the last week.
你不能把她和我扯上了
Yeah, you know what? You can't tie me to her.
你肯定会回去新泽西的  笨蛋
Who needs to? Your ass is on a plane back to New Jersey, jack off.
我为何会勾搭上那个婊子呢
Oh, man, I just... Why did I get mixed up with that bitch?
因为她的屁股很诱人
Because she got a great ass!
你不知自己在做什么
And you got your head all the way up it.
天啊
Jesus.
我很凶  是吗  当我想起屁股  女人的屁股
When I think of asses, a woman's ass...
便想起一些东西
...something comes out of me.
- 那么  - 不要你说太多
- So? - So no big thing.
我只想知道她丈夫和他那伙人
All I want is her husband and his whole fucking crew.
你会和泽加合作
Now, you're gonna work with Sergeant Drucker here.
圣金文路和赫摩撒街
San Clemente Road and Hermosa.
我们在那儿穿过栏栅
That's where we cut through the fence. That's the access.
对
Right.
保安系统不堪一击
The security systems around here are a joke.
逃走路线一是圣云逊汤玛士桥
St. Vincent Thomas Bridge, that's Escape Route Number 1.
路线二  是安纳咸公路往一一零号公路
Number 2, over here, Anaheim to the 110.
- 好  - 好吗
- Good. - Okay?
- 很好  - 明白吗  好的  走吧
- Yeah. That's fine. - Got it? Good. Let's go.
他们回头望向
They were looking back...
这方向
...in this direction.
货柜设施
A container facility?
- 什么  - 太明显了  对他们来说得益太少了
- For a cartage theft? - Too visible. Too lowball for them.
有炼油厂和废车场
Next door's an oil refinery, over there's a scrap yard.
炼油厂发薪用支票  没有现金  废车场亦一样
Refinery only pays by check. No cash around. Same for the scrap yard.
也许他们要偷车轮盖
Maybe they're stealing hubcaps.
炼油厂和废车场
A refinery and a scrap yard.
- 是什么回事  - 我们正想知道
- What the hell is going on? - That's what we're trying to figure out.
我们以为很清楚
We thought we had it.
这下倒糊涂了
Thought we had it.
我知道他们在看些什么
I got an idea of what they were looking at.
- 你们想知道吗  - 是什么
- You wanna know what they're looking at? - What?
这人真了不起  他真行
I mean, is this guy something, or is he something?
这伙人很棒
This crew is good.
你们想知道吗
You know what they were looking at?
是什么
What?
是我们
Us.
洛城警局
The L.A.P.D.
是警局
The police department.
我们给人认出了
We just got made.
是的
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
好吧  杂种
Okay, motherfucker!
祈素交出来了吗
Kelso come through?
交出来了  蓝图很详尽
Yeah, you can build a bank with these.
那人姓韩  名云信
Name is Hanna. First name Vincent.
我用五百元贿赂这警员  韩监视你一举一动
I smeared this sergeant in Vice five yards. Hanna's all over you.
监视所有的车  米高及施的家
He's on all the work cars. Michael's house, Shiherlis'.
没监视你  不知你晚上在哪儿
Not yours, they've been losing you at night.
他很积极  他毕业后加入陆战队
Hanna's a hot dog. Graduate school. Marine Corps.
是劫案及凶杀组探长
Lieutenant, Robbery-Homicide, Major Crime Unit.
拘捕过不少人  在芝加哥杀了法兰
He's taken down some heavy crews. Blew away Frankie Yonder in Chicago.
法兰是个狂人
And he was a fucking maniac.
他之前在毒品科工作  离婚两次
He was working Narcotics before that. Had some problems, divorced twice.
目前的太太叫彩钿  是他鼓动严密监视的
Current wife's Justine. He's why the extra heat.
罪案科警官
The Vice sergeant...
说韩喜欢你
...says Hanna likes you.
认为你是明星  行事很有技巧
Thinks you're some kind of star. You do this sharp, you do that sharp.
他能想到这样看他有多聪明
Look how sharp this guy is to figure that.
他像心脏病般好笑  三次婚姻
Funny as a heart attack, man. Three marriages.
你认为他喜欢待在家吗
What the fuck do you think that means? He likes staying home?
他是那种
Means the man is one of those guys out there...
整晚工作的人  很投入
...prowling around all night, dedicated.
有他和警方监视  取消劫银行吧
With this guy and this much heat, you should pass.
值得冒险一试
It's worth the stretch.
这人是否能抓住罪犯都无所谓  可你输不起
This guy can hit and miss. You can't miss once.
你肯定吗
You sure?
肯定
I'm sure.
我们去车房吧
Let's go to the garage.
彩钿
Justine.
Justine?
我们要去哪儿
Where we going?
- 好吧  你要去哪儿  - 外面
- Okay, where are you going? - Out.
- 他们用什么频道  - 九号战术频道
- What are you on? - TAC 9.
他们在四零五号公路  往机场方向北走
They're northbound out LAX on the 405. We got four ground units.
我是十八号机的韩·云信  谁和我合作
This is Vincent Hanna in Air 18. Who have I got?
我是四十号机的JJ  高·里察和我在一起
Hey, Vincent, it's JJ. I'm in Air 40. Richard Glover's with me.
车在一零五号公路  东行接近一一零号公路
It's on the 105 eastbound approaching the 110 interchange.
- 是交替追踪吗  - 是的  前面有两辆车  三辆在他后面
- You running a revolving tail? - Yeah, I got two units in front, three behind.
要其中一辆在维蒙街接我
Okay, have one of them pick me up at the Vermont on-ramp.
走吧
Let's go.
我离他有一百码吗   太近还是太远
Am I 100 yards, or what? Am I close or far, or what?
离他三百码  在中央行车线
Three hundred yards, center lane.
你好吗
How you doing?
我请你喝咖啡如何
What do you say I buy you a cup of coffee?
- 好的  走吧  - 跟着我
- Yeah, sure. Let's go. - Follow me.
你在霍森监狱七年
Seven years in Folsom.
单独囚禁三年
In the hole for three.
之前在麦尼尔监狱
McNeil before that.
那儿是一如所说的那么凶残吗
McNeil as tough as they say?
你想成为监狱学者吗
You looking to become a penologist?
你想再坐牢吗
You're looking to go back?
我追捕过不少把事情搞砸  只能束手被擒的人
You know, I chase down some crews guys just looking to fuck up,
再次送回监狱  你是那种人吗
get busted back. That you?
你拘捕的一定是饭桶笨蛋
You must've worked some dipshit crews.
我拘捕各式各样的人
I worked all kinds.
你幻想我身上有刺青
You see me doing thrill-seeking liquor-store holdups...
行劫酒铺吗
...with a "Born to Lose" tattoo on my chest?
- 不  我不会的  - 对
- No, I do not. - Right.
我不会再坐牢
I am never going back.
那么便别再行劫
Then don't take down scores.
我做擅长做的事  我行劫
I do what I do best, I take scores.
你做擅长的事  阻止我
You do what you do best, trying to stop guys like me.
你从不想过正常生活
So you never wanted a regular-type life?
是怎样的  烧烤和踢足球吗
What the fuck is that? Barbecues and ball games?
是的
Yeah.
- 你的生活正常吗  - 我的生活  不  我的生活
- This regular-type life like your life? - My life? No, my life...
一塌糊涂
No, my life's a disaster zone.
我的继女情绪深受困扰
I got a stepdaughter so fucked up...
因为她的生父是个大混蛋
...because her real father is this large-type asshole.
我有太太  我的婚姻正频临破碎边缘
I got a wife. We're passing each other on the down slope of a marriage...
第三次了
...my third...
因为我常花时间追捕你这样的人
...because I spend all my time chasing guys like you around the block.
那是我的生活
That's my life.
有人曾对我说
A guy told me one time:
若你感到附近有警方监视
Don't let yourself get attached to anything...
便不能沾上任何不能脱身的事
...you are not willing to walk out on in 30 seconds flat...
三十秒内  一走了之
...if you feel the heat around the corner.
你想捉我  我行动时你亦行动
Now, if you're on me, and you gotta move when I move...
你如何能维持婚姻呢
...how do you expect to keep a marriage?
这说法很有趣
Well, that's an interesting point.
你是僧侣吗
What are you, a monk?
我有女伴
I have a woman.
你怎么对她说
What do you tell her?
我告诉她  我是推销员
I tell her I'm a salesman.
那么若你见我从街角走来
So then, if you spot me coming around that corner...
你会离开她吗
...you're just gonna walk out on this woman?
不辞而别
Not say goodbye?
那是自律
That's the discipline.
那很空泛
That's pretty vacant, no?
正是如此
Yeah, it is what it is.
不这样做  我们还是另找职业吧
It's that, or we both better go do something else, pal.
我不懂做别的
I don't know how to do anything else.
我也不懂
Neither do I.
- 我不想做其他事  - 我也不想
- I don't much want to either. - Neither do I.
我不断重复这梦境
You know, I have this recurring dream.
我坐在偌大的餐宴席上
I'm sitting at this big banquet table...
我调查的凶案受害人均出席
...and all the victims of all the murders I ever worked are sitting at this table...
他们用黑色的眼珠子瞪望我
...and they're staring at me with these black eyeballs...
因为他们头部中枪而出血
...because they got eight-ball hemorrhages from the head wounds.
这些发胀的尸体在那儿
And there they are, these big balloon people...
因为他们被杀两周后才在床下发现
...because I found them two weeks after they'd been under the bed.
邻居报称有恶臭
The neighbors reported the smell...
他们均有出席  所有人坐在那儿
...and there they are, all of them just sitting there.
他们说什么
What do they say?
没说话
Nothing.
- 没人说话吗  - 没有
- No talk? - None.
他们无话可说
Just... They don't have anything to say.
我们彼此望着对方
See, we just look at each other.
他们望着我  就是这样  梦境是这样
They look at me. And that's it, that's the dream.
我梦过自己溺水
I have one where I'm drowning.
我得弄醒自己  开始呼吸  否则会死
And I gotta wake myself up and start breathing, or I'll die in my sleep.
你知道这象征着什么吗
You know what that's about?
知道  有足够的时间
Yeah. Having enough time.
- 有足够的时间做你想做的事吗  - 是的
- Enough time to do what you wanna do? - That's right.
- 你正在这样做吗  - 还没有
- You doing it now? - No, not yet.
我们坐在这里
You know, we're sitting here...
一如常人
...you and I, like a couple of regular fellows.
彼此做有需要的事
You do what you do, and I do what I gotta do.
现在我们见过面
And now that we've been face to face...
若我要在案发现场杀你  我会不喜欢的
...if I'm there and I gotta put you away, I won't like it.
但是
But I'll tell you...
若在你和
...if it's between you and some poor bastard...
被你杀死的人当中作选择
...whose wife you're gonna turn into a widow...
兄弟  没命的会是你
...brother, you are going down.
我有反面的看法
There's a flip side to that coin.
若你真的使我走投无路  而我要杀你呢
What if you do got me boxed in and I gotta put you down?
因为无论如何  你是无法阻止我的
Because no matter what, you will not get in my way.
是的  我们见过面
We've been face to face, yeah...
但我会毫不犹疑杀你  一秒也不迟疑
...but I will not hesitate. Not for a second.
也许会这样
Maybe that's the way it'll be.
或是谁晓得呢
Or who knows?
也许我们会永远不再见
Or maybe we'll never see each other again.
他们摆脱了我们
They dumped us.
什么
What?
- 他们逃脱了  - 什么意思
- They dumped us. - What do you mean, they dumped us?
基斯甩掉了跟踪他的探员
Chris slipped his tail.
他没跟莎莲谈及买卖的事
He doesn't talk about scores with Charlene...
我无从向马·亚伦套取资料
...so there's nothing for me to get from Marciano. I tried.
- 查·米高呢  - 亦一样
- What about Cheritto? - Same.
异频收发器放在公共汽车上
Transponders got put on a bus to San Clemente.
- 他们摆脱我们所有的监视了吗  - 是的  同一时间  晚上九时
- They dumped all our surveillance? - Yeah, at the same time. 9 p.m.
我半小时前和麦·尼尔喝咖啡
I had coffee with McCauley half an hour ago!
之后他驶往机场
We were on you. Then McCauley drives into LAX...
我们便无法飞去
...where surveillance can't fly over because of flight paths.
他的车仍在那儿  但人走了
His car's still there. He's gone.
有谁知道他们在哪儿吗
Does anybody have any idea where the fuck these people are?
他有联络吗
You hear from him yet?
没有  这令我不安  他在哪儿
Not a thing. And not hearing bothers me more. Where's this guy?
这人  我们雇用他  他说认识麦·尼尔
This guy here. We put him on. Says he knows McCauley.
你是谁
Who are you?
荣谷  我叫荣谷
Waingro. My name's Waingro.
我等他电话  你很熟识他吗
I've been living in this office day and night. How well do you know him?
我们一起做过不少大买卖
Oh, we took some major scores together.
他为何没找我
How come I haven't heard from him?
他可能忙着  但他行事很彻底
Well, he's probably busy right now, but he's real thorough.
- 他不会忘记你的  - 噢  那真令人安心
- He ain't gonna forget about you. - Oh, that's reassuring.
我可在这儿出了力
Well, I got some moves I could make here.
可能对你会很有帮助
Probably be a big help to you.
认得那烤肉的人吗
You recognize the grill man?
- 不认识  - 霍森监狱  D座的  和杜比同一囚室
- No. - Folsom. D-block. Housed with Dobie Rush.
- 我还没有小休  - 薜哥和彭曹没上班
- Ain't got my break yet, man. - Cisco and Pancho didn't show.
扔垃圾  到餐厅后抹地
Haul out the garbage. Mop up the back.
稍后再休息吧
Take your break later.
人渣  端菜
Piece of shit. Pick up.
他在哪儿
Where the hell is he?
- 我查看车场  看车是否仍在那儿  - 我也去
- I wanted to check the slot for a work car. - So did I.
是我
Yeah?
等一等
Hang on.
- 喂  - 嘿
- Yeah. - Hey.
用普通电话  拨号103-7206
Use a landline. Call me at 103-7206.
好的
All right.
- 你在哪儿  - 到处有警察监视我
- Where are you? - There's cops all over me, man.
我无法摆脱他们
They're on me like a cheap suit. I can't dump them.
- 他们知道你发现他们了吗  - 不  没有  他们平衡紧帖我
- After the fact you spotted them? - No, no. They're doing parallels.
我再试试摆脱他们
I can try to dump them again.
我怎么知道你是否摆脱了  你会引他们过来找到我们
How are we gonna know if you did? If you didn't, you'll draw them to us.
到宏杜拿去  引开他们
Head for Ventura. Pull them out of here.
好的  对不起  我真不想让你失望
All right. Hey, I'm sorry, man. Last thing I wanna do is let you down.
快点
Come on, man.
端出去
Pick up.
- 嘿  尼尔  你好吗  - 你好吗  兄弟
- Hey, hey, Neil, man. What up? - What's up, brother?
你在这儿做什么
Man, what you doing here?
我在找能够应付警方追踪的司机
What I am doing is I'm looking for a driver who can handle scanners and a radio.
现在便要
Right now, today.
你还记得吗
You remember the drill?
记得
Yeah, man, sure.
你可靠吗
You cool?
你知道我很可靠
Oh, man, now, you know I'm cool.
你现在便答覆我  肯或不肯
One answer, yes or no. Right now.
好的  去它的  我答应
Yeah, man. Fuck, yeah. You're on.
五分钟后到后面来
Out back in five.
- 是什么烧焦了  - 不是我干的
- What's burning? What's burning? - Nothing I'm doing.
是什么事
What is this?
你要去哪儿
Where do you think you're going?
刚好超过第一版的康丁斯基的色彩理论
Just came across a first edition of Kandinsky's Theory of Color.
是啊  情况很好
Yeah. No, it's in good condition.
这艘船没有停下  也没有回覆警方的喊话
And it will not stop or answer radio communication.
编号为一八零的这艘船被称为金银一号
The 180-foot vessel is called Jin Yin Number 1...
涉嫌偷渡中国非法移民
...and is suspected of smuggling Chinese illegal aliens.
警方的巡逻机于星期六发现了这艘可疑船只
It was spotted Saturday by patrol aircraft.
- 趴下  - 别动  不许动
- Stay down. - Don't move! Don't fucking move!
举起手来  举起你们的双手
Put your hands in the air! Put your hands in the air! Put them up!
趴下  两腿着地
Down, down! Get on your knees.
- 把钥匙给我  - 跪下
- Give me the keys. - Get on your knees.
跪下
Get on your knees!
过去那边  趴下
Hey. Hey! Get over there. Get the fuck... Get down.
转身  把手放在背后
Turn around! Put your hands behind you. Behind you!
趴下
Get down! Stay down!
趴下  混蛋
Get down! Get down! Down, you stupid son of a...
- 趴下  - 拿锁匙来
- Down! Down, now! - Keys! Keys! Keys!
别动
All of you stay down.
我们不想伤人  只要银行的钱  不是你们的钱
We want to hurt no one. We're here for the bank's money, not your money.
你们不会损失  政府购买了保险
Your money's insured. You're not gonna lose a dime.
想想你的家人  别冒生命危险  别逞能
Think of your families. Don't risk your life. Don't try and be a hero.
我要你们都坐在地上  手放在头上
Right now I want you to sit on the floor and put your hands on your head.
如果感到不舒服或着心脏难受  便靠在墙上
Anybody feels sick, anybody got heart trouble, go ahead and lean against the wall.
- 给我锁匙  - 什么锁匙
- Give me the key. - What key?
坐下  别动
Get down and stay down!
坐着别动  让伤口流血吧
Sit there. Sit there. Don't move. Let it bleed.
趴下
Get down!
嘿
Hey. Hey!
把头低下
Put your head down.
- 再看我一眼  我就杀了你  - 趴下
- Look at me again, I'll kill you. - Stay down. Down.
- 把头低下  - 低头  低头
- Put your head down! - Get down. Get down.
- 嘿  卡索斯  - 怎么啦
- Hey, Casals. - Yeah.
你们在调查麦·尼尔的案子吧
You guys working a case on a Neil McCauley?
机密线人许·班尼打来电话  说了关于抢劫银行的事
This CI, Hugh Benny, called in about a bank they're looking at or something.
云信
Vincent.
早上十一时半  远东国家银行
Far East National Bank, 11:30!
在第五街交界设路障
I want a block at Figueroa and 5th...
花街及第六界北行亦设路障
...and I want a block northbound Flower at 6th.
他们出来了
They're already coming out.
好的  要在车上捉他们  等他们全上车后再动手
Okay, we're gonna have to take them in the car. Wait till they are all in.
要利落地射杀他们  别伤及无辜
Get clean shots. Watch your background.
- 警察  走开  - 怎么回事
- Police! Move! - What's going on?
闪开  趴下
Move. Move. Get down.
小心
Look out.
- 让开  - 洛城警局  趴下
- Move it, come on. - L.A.P.D. Get down.
走开  趴下
Move it. Down, down, down.
我们成功了  尼尔
We did it, right, Neil? Huh?
走开
Move!
趴下
Get down.
该死
Fuck. Fuck!
开车
In the car!
走
Go! Go! Go!
- 混账东西  - 快走
- Son of a bitch! - Go, go!
走
Go!
快走
快起来  走
Come on. Come on.
带他离开这儿
Get him out of here.
趴下
Get down! Now!
见鬼
Shit.
离开这儿  快趴下
Out of the way! Down! Out of the way! Get them down! Now, now!
离开这儿
No, out of the way. Out of the way.
妈咪  妈咪
Mommy? Mommy!
过来  宝贝
Come here, honey.
来吧  孩子
Come on, honey.
我抱着你  没事儿了
I got you. It's okay now.
今天发生惨剧  银行劫案祸延街头
Tragedy in a Southland neighborhood today. A bank robbery spilled out into the street.
钮·歌迪现时在现场作最新报导
Claudia Newman, live on the scene. She has the latest. Claudia?
今天下午  抢劫银行未遂使这儿很可怕
This afternoon, this neighborhood was terrorized by a bank holdup gone wrong.
街上满是行人和孩子  警方和武装劫匪激烈交火
With the streets full of mid-day shoppers and kids, police and armed robbers...
- 劳驾  酒保  - 这就来  女士
- Excuse me, bartender? - One minute, lady.
新闻提要  劫匪逃走终于死亡
...robbery, pursuit and, finally, death.
银行劫案震动洛杉矶地区
A Los Angeles neighborhood is shaken by a bank robbery...
最后以凶杀及恐惧告终
...that ended in homicide and terror.
查·米高是四名劫匪之一
One suspect, Michael Cheritto, is one of four men involved in the foiled robbery.
- 他在现场死去  - 喝点什么  小姐
- He died at the scene. - What can I get you, miss?
另一个受重伤的疑匪  当·毕顿
Also fatally wounded, suspect Donald Breedan...
小姐
Miss?
在警方和劫匪交火时  中枪身亡
...during the extensive gunfire between police and suspects.
好了  按着他
All right, hold him. Hold him.
- 没事儿的  - 没事儿了
- All right. All right. - It's all right.
- 情况怎样  - 他失血过多  惊吓过度
- So? - Well, he's got blood loss and shock.
我给你最少量的吗啡止痛
I'm gonna give you quarter-grain morphine for the pain. Subcutaneous injection.
告诉我吧
Bottom line.
主要是组织受损  那是好事  他的锁骨折断
It's mostly tissue damage, which is good, but his clavicle's fractured.
- 能让他休息吗  - 六七个小时
- Can he rest for a while? - Six, seven hours.
- 不能多留吗  - 不能
- That's it? - That's it.
- 脱下你的衬衣  - 什么
- Take off your shirt. - What?
脱下你的衬衣
Take off your shirt.
这是女儿在父亲节送给我的
My... Look, my daughter gave it to me for Father's Day.
我不管  脱下来
I don't give a shit who gave it to you. Take it off.
基斯  嘿
Chris. Hey.
听着
Chris, listen to me.
奈德会接你  送你到他家中
Nate's gonna pick you up. He's gonna take you to his place.
- 莎莲呢  - 我们得离开这儿
- Where's Charlene? - We gotta get out of here.
新闻一直在播银行的事
We're all over the 6:00 news.
- 我们必须得走  - 没有她我不走
- We gotta get out of here. - I'm not going without her.
你考虑一下  在奈德那儿见
Think about that. I will meet you at Nate's.
你去哪儿
Where are you going?
查探逃走路线是否给泄露了
I gotta find out if our out got spilled along with every other damn thing.
是谁告密的
Who did it?
有谁没参加
Who wasn't there?
齐祖
Trejo.
在奈德家见
I'll see you at Nate's.
- 是的  - 你仍想要我吗
- Yeah. - Yeah. You still want me?
你来这里接我和多明吧
You come down here right now and you get me. Dominick and me. Okay?
好的  宝贝  我两小时后到
Okay, baby, okay. I'll be there in two hours, all right?
- 好吗  - 好吧
- Okay? - All right.
你真该死  基斯  你真该死
Goddamn you, Chris. Goddamn you.
- 你坐飞机前往洛杉矶  - 太好了
- You're on a plane for Los Angeles. - Great.
你为何这样做  怎么回事
Why'd you do it? What happened?
- 他们逼迫我  - 谁
- They made me. - Who?
安娜呢
Where's Anna?
她死了
She's dead.
米高和代替你的毕顿亦死了
So is Michael and Breedan, the guy who stood in for you.
- 谁迫害你的  是谁 -  他们威胁安娜
- Who did it? Who did it? - They had Anna, man.
谁威胁她
Who had her?
荣谷
Waingro.
他一个人吗
On his own?
- 替人卖命  - 谁
- For someone. - Who?
他替别人工作
The other he worked for.
宏山
Zant.
- 宏山  - 对
- Van Zant? - Yeah.
宏山
Van Zant.
- 你肯定吗  - 宏山
- Are you sure? - Van Zant.
你有说出我们怎样逃走吗
Did you say anything about how we're getting out?
- 我认为没有  - 说吧
- I don't think so, Neil. - Come on.
我不记得了
I don't remember, Neil.
- 我通知救护员  - 我无法活下去的
- I'll call a medic. - I'm not gonna make it.
我全无感觉
I can't feel nothing.
我的安娜死了
My Anna's gone.
她死了
She's gone.
别这样扔下我  尼尔  求求你  朋友
Don't leave me like this, Neil. Please, holmes.
别这样扔下我
Don't leave me like this.
- 喂  - 奈德
- Yeah? - Nate.
你用无线电话吗  用普通电话
You on a cellular? Use a hard line.
这是新的电话
It's a new one.
他住在安仙奴区山景台
The guy lives on Hillside Terrace, Encino.
- 一零七二五号  - 一零七二五号  好的
- 10725. - 10725, okay.
- 基斯呢  - 他和我一起在我家中
- Chris? - He's with me, at my place.
跟着查出荣谷在哪儿
Next, Waingro, okay?
你有时间吗
You got the time?
我会抽空的  我需要新的逃走路线
I'll make time, and I need a new out laid on.
你怎么知道被泄露了呢
How do you know it's blown?
我怎么能相信没泄露呢
How can I trust it?
好的  没问题
Okay, you got it.
保住性命
Stay healthy.
莎莲
Charlene Shiherlis.
泽加在威尼斯区有地方收藏她
Drucker's got a safe house in Venice to stash her in.
尼尔的逃走方法
Our Neil's transportation. When we're done here, get on the phone.
正有人替他安排一切
Somewhere, someone's trying to put it together for him.
你不会认为他已经有计划了吧
You don't believe McCauley already had a getaway?
他当然有计划  但他需要另一个计划  换成你还能相信原来的计划吗
Sure he did. Now he needs another one. Would you trust yours after this afternoon?
这告密的混蛋  哪儿找到他的
This rat motherfucker, where did we get him?
他是机密线人  通报劫银行线索
He's a CI for a burglary cop. Called in the tip on the bank.
谈谈麦·尼尔吧  还有多少时间
On Neil McCauley, how much time we got?
他有八至十小时安排新逃走路线  之后  他就走了
Eight, 10 hours for him to set up a new out. After that, he's gone.
拜拜了
Bye-bye. Bam.
你向我们告发麦·尼尔  你怎么知道  谁告诉你的
You ratted McCauley to us. How'd you know? Who told you?
是谁告诉你的  混蛋
Who told you, you rat motherfucker?
是谁
Who?
康尼回来阻击墨菲  墨菲在奋力拼抢
Connelly back in for Murphy. Murphy with Leggat right there with him.
得球后  准备打门
Murphy tees it up behind the net...
米勒也冲到了前场
...Miller out front. Now here's Murphy with the referee...
荣谷在哪儿
Waingro, where is he?
- 在哪儿  - 我怎么知道
- Where is he? - How the hell would I know?
嗯  这儿有些什么
Well, what do we have here, hmm?
这儿漂亮吗  漂亮吗
Isn't this pretty? It's pretty.
- 你这个小人  - 你告诉我想脱离目前的困境
- You slimy piece of shit. - You told me you wanted out from under.
你想脱身吗  这是出路
You're scared to death, right? You want out? This is out, Charlene.
- 你得到什么好处啦  - 我没好处  你这个蠢娘们
- Yeah, what's your end? - I... You stupid broad.
- 我怎么会牵涉此事的  - 嘿  冷静  别冲动
- How'd I get into this? - Hey, hey, hey. Easy.
你听到我说的了
You heard me.
她已经够难受的了  你为何不给她倒杯酒呢
She had a rough ride. Why don't you fix her a drink or something?
- 到橱柜看看  - 去她的
- Look in the cabinet above the sink. - Fuck her.
- 你最好进去  不要出来  - 好吧
- You'd better get in there and stay in there. - All right, all right.
看看这儿
Well, lookie here.
我是泽加  洛城警局  凶杀组探员
My name is Sergeant Drucker, L.A.P.D. Homicide.
- 要送多明进睡房吗  - 他和我待在一起
- You wanna put Dominick in the bedroom? - He stays with me.
坐下
There we go.
现在怎么办
So, what now?
他说得对  你想脱身  这是出路
Well, he's right, because you want out, this is out.
- 你真的要出卖基斯吗  - 正是
- You believe you have to betray Chris. - No shit.
这就对了  你是得这样做
That's right. You would have to.
若不出卖基斯  多明会是受害人
See, if you don't betray Chris, you victimize Dominick.
因为当你入狱时  他便会成为孤儿
Because he becomes an orphan when you go to prison as an accessory...
你也没有父母来照顾他
...because you got no living parents to take him.
他会被送进收养所  青少年中心
So he ends up state-raised in foster homes, juvenile facilities.
之后他会偷车
Then he steals a car.
然后入狱学会做真正的罪犯
Then he winds up in gladiator academies like Chino and Tracy.
毁了一生
Fucked for life.
你是过来人  知道会有何下场
You know what happens, because you've been there.
多明没机会选择生活  但基斯有
Dominick didn't get a chance yet to choose his life, but Chris did.
你若供出基斯  你会没有案底
If you give up Chris, you get off clean.
你可以为了孩子而这样做  你可以抚养他
You can do it for your kid, so you can raise him.
- 你还有什么条件  - 各种各样的东西
- What else are you selling? - All kinds of shit.
但我不用说服你  因为我是对的
But I don't have to sell this and you know it, because this kind of shit here sells itself.
最新消息
Okay, Danny, here's an update.
- 泽加在二线  - 等一等
- Drucker's on Line 2. - Lieutenant, hold on for a second.
泽加在另一电话线
Lieutenant, I have Drucker on the other line.
三人通话吧
Oh, well, conference him in.
- 说吧  - 云信  是我
- Go ahead. - Vincent, it's me.
你的答覆是怎样的
I want an answer. What's it gonna be?
我们准备好了  她会打电话
We're set here. She'll make the call.
好的  情况是这样
Okay, that's good. Here's the deal here.
许·班尼已改过自新  成为洗心革面的好市民
Hugh Benny has reformed his wayward life and become a born-again good citizen.
叫荣谷的人向我们出卖了尼尔
Apparently, Neil got sold out to us by this cowboy named Waingro.
荣谷曾是他手下
Waingro used to be a part of Neil's crew...
后替洗钱人工作  他叫宏山
...then he went to work for a money launderer named Van Zant.
现时正派人前住宏山家中  因为他今晚较早前被杀
Units are at Van Zant's house as we speak because he got shot dead earlier tonight.
尼尔要对付的人会是荣谷
Now, if Neil goes after anybody else, it's gonna be Waingro.
荣谷正入住侯爵机场酒店套房
Waingro just got himself a suite at the airport Marquis...
并化名詹美臣  他正在那儿
...under the name "Jameson". He's there now.
我要你把这消息告诉外围带家
I want you to get that to bail bondsmen, bookies...
奉派警员及线人
...assignment officers and snitches in County.
任何能把消息外泄的人
Anyone you can think of who'll put it on the street.
派人到酒店驻守  并每隔半小时收听无线电
Deploy a team at the hotel and personally check their come every 30 minutes.
也许尼尔会杀他  明白吗  你感觉怎么样
Because maybe Neil will go for him. Okay? How you feeling?
- 不算太惨  我会活着  - 很好
- Banged up, but I'll live. - Okay.
他仍在
He's here.
尼尔还没走
Neil is still here.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
会留多久
But for how long?
最多七八个小时
Seven, eight hours, max.
你做过什么
What did you do?
- 是你做的吗  - 我不是卖金属的
- That was you? - It's what I don't do, I don't sell metal.
计划原本顺利  但现在出了麻烦
Would have been okay, you fly out after. Now it's jammed.
- 我们要一起走  - 那些人和你一起的吗
- Now we gotta go together. - Those other people were with you?
我的朋友米高
My friend, Michael...
他知道所冒的险
...he knew the risks. He didn't have to be there.
身处险境便要冒生命危险
It rains, you get wet.
收拾东西
Get packed and let's go.
伊荻
Eady.
你为何这样对我
Why did you do this to me?
你究竟是谁
Who are you?
不会有事的  明白吗
It's gonna be all right. You understand? It'll be all right.
不会有事的
It's gonna be all right.
不会的
Right.
这个地址  D层十八单位  有一辆汽车
There's this Camaro at this address, Level D, Slot 18.
这儿有现金
Here's some cash.
此事何时了解
When's it over?
二十二小时后
22 hours from now.
- 那时我们便可脱身  - 那时你会让我离开吗
- Then we get out of here clean. - When will you let me leave?
那现在就走吧  你想离开吗  门在那边
Go now. You want out? There's the door.
你稍后会让我离开吗
Will you let me leave later?
情况会不同
It will be different.
你还不明白吗
Do you understand?
准备好了
It's ready.
云信
Vincent.
这是我的朋友洛夫
This is my friend Ralph.
你没说你已已经
You didn't tell me you were...
- 天啊  - 罗兰在哪儿
- Oh, my God. - Where's Lauren?
- 她在碧芙家中  - 听着  此事和我无关
- She's at Lisa-Beth's. - Look, this has nothing to do with me.
- 我不知道  对不起  - 对不起什么  坐下
- I didn't know. I'm terribly sorry. - What are you sorry about? Sit down.
你不生气吗
Don't you even get angry?
我当然生气
I'm angry, yeah.
我非常生气  洛夫
I'm very angry, Ralph.
若她想要你干她  你可以干我太太
You know, you can ball my wife if she wants you to.
你可以躺在她的沙发上
You can lounge around here on her sofa.
在她前夫的
In her ex-husband's...
高科技后现代主义的荒谬家中  若你想的话
...dead-tech, post-modernistic, bullshit house, if you want to...
但你不能看我该死的电视机
...but you do not get to watch my fucking television set!
天啊
For God's sake.
把电视机放下
Put the television set down.
- 我没对你不忠  贱货  - 也许你应该
- I never cheated on you, bitch. - Maybe you should have.
- 我应该吗  - 你对此也有责任
- I should have? - In a way, you're a party to this.
没错  我要洛夫干你  因为这使我开心
Oh, yeah. I made Ralph fuck you because it makes me feel good.
我们的处境荒谬
Our situation is absurd.
- 听着  也许我该走了  - 住口  洛夫  坐下
- Look, maybe I should... - Shut up, Ralph. Sit down!
我为何要向你把事情解释清楚  你又做什么了
Why is it that I have to figure things out and explain them to you? What do you do?
- 我说话算话  亦言出必行  - 哼  多么可敬
- I say what I mean, and I do what I say. - Mm, how admirable.
- 那当然  - 可是没什么是和我们有关的
- You bet. - Except none of it's about us.
是的
No.
我一定是抽大麻或服兴奋剂迷糊了
I may be stoned on grass and Prozac...
但你在我们的生活中犹如死了
...but you've been walking through our life dead.
我不得不作践自己  找洛夫来终断我们的关系
Now I have to demean myself with Ralph just to get closure with you.
护照  旅行支票  信用卡
Passports, traveler's checks, plastic.
这飞机  在洛城机场包机站十七号机库
The plane, charter terminal, LAX, Hangar 17.
确定密码是一零一一山岭
Call letters are 1011 Sierra.
飞机会降落  等你五分钟  然后便起飞
Touches down, holds for you five minutes, then splits.
飞机会通过航空局检查等手续
The plane will stand an FAA check. Filed a flight plan, the works.
- 基斯呢  - 他走了
- Hey, where's Chris? - He's gone.
什么
What?
他说去找莎莲  他走了
Said he's going on his own. Went to look for Charlene.
- 是你带他来这儿的吗  - 是的  我带他来了
- Didn't you bring him here? - Yeah, I brought him here.
怎么回事
What happened?
这是个自由国家
It's a free country, brother.
晚上九时联络我  确保一切妥当
Check in with me at 9. Everything's still cool.
好的
All right.
我甚至不知道自己在做什么
I don't even know what I'm doing anymore.
我知道人生苦短
I know life is short.
能活多久是运气
Whatever time you get is luck.
你想终断这段关系
You wanna walk?
你现在就能离开
You walk right now.
或者你自愿
Or on your own...
你自愿选择跟我一起走
On your own, you choose to come with me.
我只知道
All I know is...
我无论到任何地方去  都将失去意义
All I know is there's no point in me going anywhere anymore...
因为只有我独自一人
...if it's gonna be alone...
没有你陪在身边
...without you.
伊荻
Eady.
- 喂  - 云信  我抓了个活的
- Yeah. - Yeah, Vincent, I got a live one.
好  我等着
Okay, I'll hold.
过去  让基斯看见你
Come on, sugar. Show yourself.
- 快去啊  - 住口
- Yeah, do it. - Shut up!
只需在窗前站一秒
Now, just one second at the window...
此事便会了结
...and it's all over.
朋友
Hey, man.
- 干嘛  - 你知道
- Yeah? - You know any, uh...
这附近有地方要出租吗
...place to rent around here?
知道
Yeah.
那边墙上有告示
Alberiz's Grocer on Dell Avenue got cards on the wall.
好的  谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
不是他  不是基斯
It's not him. It's not Chris.
是指挥部
Unit 2, this is Command.
拦住他  核实他的身份
Take him at the street and check him out.
收到
10-4.
- 警官  - 说
- Sergeant? - Yeah.
他叫庄·彼得  有效的身份证
This guy's John Peterson. Valid ID.
车辆登记人是布·基赞
Car's registered to the last name Bukowski, first name Gene.
向运输署查核过  没有不妥
Ran it to DMV. It's clean.
- 让他走  - 收到
- Let him go. - Roger.
非常感谢  祝你晚安
Thank you very much. Have a good evening.
不是他  云信
It's a no-go, Vince.
我们等时你想喝咖啡吗
Would you like a cup of coffee while we wait, Mrs. Shiherlis?
那会很不错
Yeah, that'd be nice.
- 喂  - 你有什么消息
- Yeah? - Yeah, what do you got?
没事发生
Nothing's happening.
- 喂  - 我是云信
- Yeah? - Hello, it's Vincent.
有何动静
What do you got?
没有  荣谷去拿冰块了
Nothing's going on. Waingro went for ice. That's it.
你知道吗
You know what?
尼尔跑了
Neil is gone.
走了
Bam!
- 像鸟儿般飞走  - 行了  云信  你怎么知道
- Flying like a bird. - Come on, Vincent, how do you know?
- 我们还有机会  也许仍有时间  - 得了  我们有什么
- We still got bait. Maybe some time! - Got, got. What do we got?
我们有什么
What do we got?
一路顺风  混蛋
Bon voyage, motherfucker.
你很了不起
You were good.
我要回酒店去
I'm going to the hotel.
我要洗澡
I'm gonna take a shower.
好好睡觉  睡一个月
Gonna sleep for a month.
来
Over here.
醒来吧
Come on, baby.
好了
Okay, okay.
不要
Shit.
让我绑紧胳膊
Let me tighten this.
浪费生命
What a fucking waste.
好了  来了
Okay, here.
每天都有混蛋自杀  但你不是混蛋  宝贝  你不会死的
Assholes shoot themselves all fucking day. Not you, baby. Not you.
她会在哪儿  她叫罗兰  古·罗兰
Where would she be? Her name is Lauren, Lauren Gustafson.
她该在这儿的
I'm supposed to be here with her. But the police...
- 我要人帮忙  - 没事儿的
- Help me. I need somebody to help... - It's okay.
我抱着你
I got you.
我抱着你呢  宝贝
I got you, baby.
你会没事的  你会没事的  宝贝
It'll be all right, honey. I swear. It's okay, baby.
快找医生来  你妈妈来了
Let's get a doctor! Let's go! A doctor here! There's your mama.
- 冷静下来  - 你妈妈在这儿
- Let's just calm down. - Your mama's here.
- 她是吸毒了吗  - 不是
- Is she on any drugs? - No.
找精神创伤及血管医生来
I want you to get a trauma surgeon and a vascular surgeon.
她割断了两条动脉  我摸不到她的脉搏
I think she cut both arteries. Also, I could hardly feel her pulse.
她的血压很低  呼吸也很微弱  要给她插管
Her pressure's down. So is her respiration. You have to intubate her.
准备好了
It's ready.
- 最后一次见她时是什么时候  - 我不知道
- When's the last time anybody saw her? - I don't know.
- 你在哪儿找到她的  - 浴缸
- Where did you find her? - The bathtub.
给她注射大针管的盐水
Call Respiratory stat. Give her large-bore normal saline. Wide open.
紧按出血的血管  先输入两个单位O型血
Let's keep pressure on those bleeders. I need two units, O-negative.
- 查明血型后再输入六个单位相同的  - 看来她已经窦性心律过速
- Let's type and cross her for six. - Looks like she's in sinus tach.
呼吸专家呢  我们需要帮忙
Where is Respiratory? We need more help.
快叫呼吸科医生过来
Can you have Respiratory come now?
准备插管后照X光
Let's have x-ray ready for post-intubation chest x-ray.
嗨  你的女儿已经做好手术  正在疗养室
Hi. Your daughter's out of surgery and she's in the recovery room now, okay?
她情况稳定  医生很快会跟你说
Her vital signs are stable. The surgeon will be out to speak to you in a few moments.
- 她没事吧  - 她很好
- She's okay? - She's doing good.
- 她会好起来的  - 她会好起来的
- She's gonna be okay. - She's gonna be okay.
- 噢  我的宝贝  - 她会好起来的  没事了
- Oh, my baby. - She's gonna be okay. It's all right.
- 没事了  - 她为何这样对待自己
- It's all right. - Why'd she do this to herself? Why?
看她把自己怎么了
Look what she did. Look what she did to herself.
好了
There.
没事的  不会有事的
It's all right, honey. It's gonna be all right.
我在这儿  不会到别处去
I'm here. I ain't going anywhere.
- 明白吗  - 嗯
- You understand? - Yeah.
我不会到别处去
I ain't going anywhere.
喂
Yeah?
是我
It's me.
飞机已在半空  你得准时到达
Plane's in the air now. It'll be right on time.
可信任的司机仍找不到
On the driver's end, I still can't find nobody, so that's in the trust.
还有一事
One other thing.
你问过我  所以我得告诉你
You asked, so I gotta tell you.
你找的人在候爵酒店  化名詹美臣
The guy you wanted checked into the Marquis under "Jameson"...
我看你不想找他了吧
...if you still give a shit, which I figured you wouldn't.
- 你说得对  - 那么  再见  兄弟
- You figured right. - So, so long, brother.
多保重
You take it easy.
你自由了
You're home free.
你也保重
Take it easy.
- 什么事  - 没事
- What is it? - Nothing.
自由了
Home free.
- 我得解决一些事情  - 还有时间吗
- I gotta take care of something. - Is there time?
有的
There's time.
我很快回来  让车子开动吧
I'll be right back. Just leave her running.
- 入住登记处  - 我是房间餐饮部
- Registration. - Yeah, this is Room Service.
詹美臣要了食物  但房号弄错了  你能告诉我吗
A Jameson ordered a BLT. They screwed up his room number. Could you give it to me?
- 他们经常会弄错  - 我知道
- They're always doing that. - Yeah, I know.
- 是一七三五号房  - 谢谢
- 1735. - Thank you.
请注意
Your attention, please.
现在响起火警警报
We are currently experiencing a fire alarm.
不用惶恐  不要乘坐升降机
Please do not panic. Please do not take the elevators.
该死  荣谷没走  我留在这儿
Shit. Waingro's not moving. I'm staying here.
我查看楼梯  若有烟  便会要你走
I'm checking the stairs. If there's smoke, I'm pulling you out.
我该通知她父亲吗
What about her dad? You want me to call him?
他在内华达山脉某处
He's somewhere in the Sierras.
她选择了你
And she chose you.
选择在你的房间自杀
She picked your place.
这样做是不对的  不该发生在她身上
It's not right, what happened to her.
是的
No, it's not.
好了
Ugh, okay.
是否有方法
Is there any way...
能克服我们之间的问题
...that it could work out between us?
我希望说有
I wish I could say yes, you know.
可是  到最后
But in the end...
就像你说的
You know, it's like you said:
我沉迷于  追捕我的罪犯
All I am, is what I'm going after.
我不是你想要的人
I'm not what you want, Justine.
若你要走  便走吧
Well, go on, if you have to.
不
No.
- 我会留下  - 我没事  我可以应付
- I'll stay. - No, I'm okay. I can... I can handle this.
你保重
Just be careful.
给我打电话  让我知道你没事
Call me here. Let me know you're okay.
好吗
Okay?
走楼梯
Take the stairs.
干嘛
Yeah?
酒店保安  三楼发生火警  各楼层的人都要疏散
Security. There's a fire on 3. We have to evacuate all the floors.
我不能离开
I can't leave here.
我们何不先谈一下  兄弟
Why don't we just talk about this a bit, huh, brother?
他在十七楼
He's here on 17.
看着我  看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
看着我
Look at me.
洛城警方  别动  把手放在头上
L.A.P.D. Don't move. Put your hands on your head, now.
将我转到五号频道
Switch me to TAC 5.
卡索斯  JJ
Casals? JJ?
泽加  JJ
Drucker, JJ?
我在大堂接近楼梯井
I'm at the lobby level by the stairwell.
出了什么事
What have you got?
小组搭乘另一升降机前往十七楼
Teams are moving up the other elevators to the 17th floor elevators.
因为火警警钟响起  升降机不能用
All out of commission because of the fire alarm.
- 这里一团糟  人山人海  - 好的  知道了
- It's a mess. People everywhere. - Fine. 10-4.
快走  不要挡道
Let's go, get out of the way.
不要挡道
Stay out of the way.
快走  快离开
Let's go. Go that way. We gotta go, all right? Go, go.
让我来  先生
I got it, sir.
快走
Come on, come on.
快走  先生
Come on, sir.
- 小心后面  女士们  - 我搞定了
- Watch your backs, ladies. - I got it, I got it.
继续走  夫人
Keep moving, ma'am.
走吧
Let's go.
快点  走吧
Come on, let's go.
走这边  夫人
This way, ma'am.
后退  后退
Get back, get back.
- 把枪给我  - 是  长官
- Let me have that shotgun. - Yes, sir.
跟你说过  我不会再回到监狱
Told you I'm never going back.
是啊
Yeah.